《尖峰时刻3》
你在干吗？
What the hell are you doing?
什么情况？
What the hell?!
谁让你开了 见鬼
I didn't tell you to go! Goddamn!
- 是他 - 是你
- It was him! - It was you!
噢 我的天啊
Shit! Oh, man!
没人听指挥了
Ain't nobody listening today.
女士 你刚刚挡住了一辆81奥兹莫比尔
Ladies, you just dented a '81 Cutlass Supreme.
我需要看一下你们的驾照和注册证件
I need to see your license and registration.
老兄 你没事吧？还好吧？
Brother, you OK? You cool?
10分钟 听我的信号开门
Ten minutes. Doors open on my signal.
我很高兴你能在这里 李
I'm glad you're here, Lee.
有你在我觉得很放心
I always feel better with you watching my back.
我只是在尽我的职责 大使先生
I'm just doing my job, Mr. Ambassador.
今天跟紧我 李
Stay close today, Lee.
我们在创造历史
We're making history.
这简直是扯蛋 你知道我是谁吗？
This is bullshit! Do you know who I am?
我的家族掌管着罗迪欧大道的半条街
My family owns half of Rodeo Drive.
那你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
我是洛杉矶警局的詹姆斯·卡特警官
Detective James Carter, LAPD.
我们家掌管着科伦尚大道的半条街
My family owns half of Crenshaw Boulevard.
我需要一个律师
I want a lawyer.
你需要一个私人健身教练
You need a personal trainer.
驾照上说你有180磅
This license says 180 pounds.
但你比这车还沉 姑娘
You weigh more than the damn car, girl.
- 我甲状腺有问题 - 那就不要吃甲状腺了
- I have a thyroid condition. - Well, stop eating thyroids.
听着 难道这次就不能只给个警告之类的吗？
Look, can't you just, like give us a warning or something?
这要看情况了 你们喜欢中国人吗？
That depends. You girls like Chinese?
不好意思
Excuse me.
卡特
Carter.
李 今晚聚一聚吧
Lee, we are on for tonight.
我找到了两个愿意和亚洲警察在一起的妹子
I just picked up two girls who wanna play hide the little Asian policeman.
我现在不方便说话 我正和韩大使在车上
I can't talk now. I'm in the car with Ambassador Han.
相信我 这俩女孩可靓了
Trust me, these girls are sushi grade.
- 千万不要错过哟 - 我得挂了 不好意思
- We gotta hit this! - I have to go. I'm sorry.
你还在生我的气 是吗？
You're still mad at me, aren't you?
还在为在纽约发生的事生气
You're mad because of what happened when we was in New York.
我不想再谈那个
I don't want to talk about that.
都过去三年了 忘了吧
It was three years ago. When you gonna let it go?
忘了？伊莎贝拉是我的女朋友
Let it go? Isabella was my girlfriend.
李 我们是朋友 哥们
Lee, we're friends, man.
就和我出来一个晚上吧
Just come out with me one night.
我请你吃木须肉
The mu shu's on me.
李
Lee!
哈
Ha.
我妈妈让我给您问好
My mom says hi.
中国的三合会目前有50万成员
The Chinese triads now have half a million members...
散布在100多个国家
in over 100 countries.
他们已不再是敲诈当地商人的小混混了
And these are not street kids shaking down local merchants.
而是成为了花费500亿美金 建立地下帝国的商人
These are businessmen who have built a $50 billion empire...
从事敲诈 贩毒 卖淫和奴隶交易
of extortion, drugs, sex and slavery.
我们要在它将我们吞没之前 将其斩草除根
We must cut off the head of this snake before it swallows us whole.
作为世界刑事法庭的主席
As chairman of the World Criminal Court...
我已经委托我的好朋友韩大使来受理此事
I have entrusted my good friend Ambassador Han to lead the fight...
与世界上最大的犯罪组织抗衡
against the largest criminal organization in the world.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
瑞纳德主席 女士们先生们
Chairman Reynard, ladies and gentlemen.
三合会是一个秘密建立的组织
The triad society is built on secrecy.
没有人知道他们是谁 谁是幕后的主使
Nobody knows who these men are, who controls them, who leads them.
500年来没有人知道
Nobody has known for 500 years.
但是今天 我带着一个秘密来到这里
But today, I stand before you with a secret of my own.
今天 我将会公布一个令在座每一位震惊的消息
Today, I will disclose information that affects everyone in this room.
经过几年的寻找 我确认已经找到了"煞星"
After years of searching, I believe I've finally located Shy Shen.
大使先生 "煞星"根本就不存在
Mr. Ambassador, Shy Shen does not exist.
不好意思 这个"煞星"是谁？
Excuse me, who is this Shy Shen?
恕我冒昧地说 先生 我…
With all due respect, sir, I le...
大家爬下
Everybody down!
叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
找个医生过来
Someone get a doctor.
大使被击中了 大使被击中了
Ambassador down, Ambassador down.
待在他身边
Stay with him.
呃呃呃 在今晚见你们之前我会保管的
Uh-uh-uh. Keeping these till I see you tonight.
各方注意 世界刑事大厦发生枪击
Attention all units, shots have been fired at the World Criminal Court building.
中国大使被击中
The Chinese Ambassador has been shot.
中国大使？让开
Chinese Ambassador? Move your asses over.
- 让开 - 什么？哦 见鬼
- Move over! - What? Whoa. Shit!
你在干什么？
What're you doing?!
李
Lee!
- 他到底要去哪里？- 啊
- Where the hell is he goin'? - Ah!
洛杉矶警局 都他妈给我闪开
LAPD! Get the hell outta the way!
人们都疯了
People are crazy.
等我回来我会好好收拾你的
I'm-a give your ass a ticket when I come back!
李 我来了
Lee, I'm comin'!
不许动
Don't move!
你好啊 李
Hello, Lee.
健二 不准动
李 你还在等什么？开枪打我啊
这样也许能有点帮助
放下枪 不然我开枪了
我想我们彼此都知道 你是不会那么做的
I think we both know that's not gonna happen.
健二
Kenji!
看到没？我对你太了解了
You see? I know you too well.
- 唔 - 李 你没事吧？
- Ungh. - Lee, you OK?
我差点要了你的小命 你为什么不闪开啊？
We almost killed your ass. Why you didn't move?
我来给你介绍一下今晚的两位女士 玛莎和祖拉
I'd like for you to meet our dates for this evenin'. Masha and Zoe.
胖子是你的
Fat one's yours.
你想让我说多少遍？我很抱歉
How many times do you want me to say it? I'm sorry.
我很抱歉差点撞到你 哥们 见鬼
I'm sorry I ran you over, man. Damn!
不是现在 卡特
Not now, Carter.
好了 就站在那里 什么都不要说 卡特
All right, hold it right there. Don't say a word, Carter.
迪尔长官 我与这件事没有任何关系
Captain Diel, I had nothing to do with this.
我所作的只是借了辆车 帮李解围
All I did was borrow a car, backed up Lee.
告诉他 老搭档
Tell him, partner.
我需要见韩大使
I need to see Ambassador Han.
大使刚做完手术
The Ambassador is just out of surgery.
子弹没有射中心脏 他不会有事的
The bullet missed his heart. He's gonna be OK.
长官 你必须给我复职
Captain, you have to give me back my shield...
让我参与这个案子 我只是犯了一个小错误
and put me on this case. I made one little mistake.
- 别让我坐冷板凳 - 一个小错误？
- Take a brother off the bench. - One little mistake?
你铐住了两个女士还抢了她们的车
You handcuffed two women and stole their car.
不然为什么要买保险？
Isn't that why we have insurance?
每个人都有倒霉的时候 长官
Everyone has an off day, Captain.
上个月你让六个伊朗人蹲了一个星期的牢
Last month you put six Iranians in jail for a week!
你和我都知道那些伊朗人是恐怖分子
You and I both know them Iranians was terrorists.
他们是加州大学的科学家
They were scientists at UCLA!
这有什么大不了的
Big deal.
就因为他们在小鼠身上治愈了癌症…
'Cause they cure cancer in rats...
那不代表他们就不会制造爆炸
that doesn't mean they won't blow shit up.
让我负责来寻找凶手
Let me find the person who shot Ambassador Han.
放松 卡特 洛杉矶警局不会插手此事的调查
Relax, Carter. The LAPD won't be leading this investigation.
保护大使是我的职责
The Ambassador is my responsibility.
那么也许你可以告诉我 凶手是怎么逃走的
Well, then maybe you could tell me exactly how that shooter got away.
什么都不用说了
Thought so.
大使的女儿正在过来的路上
The Ambassador's daughter is coming to see her father right now.
确保她别再出什么事
Make sure nothing happens to her.
放心吧 长官 我们不会让你丢脸的
Don't worry, Captain, we're gonna make you proud.
别再想你妻子离开你的事了
And try not to think about your wife leaving you.
她会回来的
She'll come back.
苏阳也来了？
Soo Yung's here?
她十岁以后我就没有再见过她
I haven't seen her since she was ten years old.
她现在就住在洛杉矶
She lives in Los Angeles now.
我们去礼品店给她买一个小泰迪熊吧
Let's go to the gift shop and get her a little teddy bear.
已经这么"大"了
And a bra.
- 李 - 苏阳
- Lee! - Soo Yung.
我真的很高兴你能在这里
I'm so glad you're here.
- 卡特警官 - 苏阳
- Detective Carter. - Soo Yung.
- 好久不见了 - 是啊 苏阳
- It's been so long. - So long, Soo Yung.
这么年轻…
So... So young.
- 他怎么样了？- 刚做完手术
- How is he? - He's out of surgery.
他们说他会没事的
They said he'll be OK.
苏阳 对不起
Soo Yung, I'm sorry.
我没有好好照顾你的父亲 都是我的错 对不起
我希望你们两个能答应我一件事
I want you both to promise me something.
我希望你们找到暗杀我父亲的凶手
I want you to find the man who did this to him.
我希望你们能找到他 因为只要我父亲还活着
I want you to find him because I don't think he'll stop...
他就不会甘休
until my father is dead.
苏阳
Soo Yung.
我希望你们答应我
I need to hear you say it.
好的 我答应你
OK, I promise.
我也是
And so do I.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
苏阳 你父亲在遇害前 正在法庭上发言
Soo Yung, your father was addressing the court before he was shot.
两周前 我父亲寄给我了一个信封
Two weeks ago, my father mailed me an envelope.
他说如果有什么不测的话…
He said if anything ever happened to him...
- 就让我把它交给你 - 在哪里？
- I should give it to you. - Where is it?
我把它放在我任教的武馆的柜子里了
I put it in my locker at the kung-fu studio where I teach.
地址是唐人街第一街
It's at 8347 First Street...
8347号
Chinatown.
回家去吧 卡特 这件事与你无关
Go home, Carter. This has nothing to do with you.
我刚才和你一样 也答应过苏阳了
I made Soo Yung a promise, the same as you.
这是中国的事情
This is the business of China.
好吧 告诉你 我现在是半个中国人了
Well, for your information, I'm part Chinese now.
是真的 李 过去的三年里我诵读了
That's right, Lee. For the last three years I've studied...
古代的佛经 现在是武术黑带两段
the ancient teachings of Buddha, earning two black belts...
并且每天下午都在
in wushu martial arts, spending every afternoon...
皮克邦迪大街上的香港花园按摩院作按摩
at the Hong Kong Garden massage parlor on Pico and Bundy.
我是半个中国人 宝贝
I am half-Chinese, baby.
如果你是半个中国人 那我就是半个黑人了
If you're half-Chinese, I'm half-black.
我是你同胞 我就会飞了 明白了吗 史努比？
I'm your brother and I'm fly. You down with that, Snoopy?
这种想法很愚蠢不是吗？
That's dope, isn't it?
不好意思 李 你当不了黑人 因为你身高不够
Sorry, Lee, you can't be black. There's a height requirement.
就像坐马特洪雪橇
Same as riding the Matterhorn.
回去吧 卡特
Go home, Carter.
我不能把你一个人留在这里 李
I can't leave you, Lee.
永远的朋友
Friends forever.
我不能抛下我的兄弟不管
Can't leave my brother.
好的 听着 都看我这边
All right, listen up! I need everyone's attention.
我是卡特警官 这位是李督察
I'm Detective Carter, this is Inspector Lee.
我们要看一下苏阳的柜子 现在就要
We need to see Soo Yung's locker right now.
没有师父的允许谁都不能到后边去
No one's allowed in the back without the master's permission.
听见我刚才说的了吗 我们要看那个柜子
Maybe you didn't hear me. We need to see that locker.
- 对不起 - 等一下 卡特
- I'm sorry. - Wait. Carter.
李 交给我好了
Lee, I got this.
嘿 嘿嘿 孩子们
Hey! Heh heh. Kids.
听着 武力解决不了任何问题
Listen. Violence will solve nothing.
就像中国一句古话说的 君子动口不动手
Now, as the Chinese say, all great battles are won without fighting.
- 对不起 - 明白了吗？
- Sorry. - OK?
我不认识他
I don't know him.
好的 我们都冷静一下 把这个放下…
Now, let's just calm down and put this...
- 哈 - 哦
- Haa! - Ow!
该死
God da...
好吧…
OK...
敬酒不吃吃罚酒
I tried talking.
噢 我要把你们打得落花流水
Hoo! Now I'm about to beat the puberty out of y'all.
有种过来 有种过来 来啊
You ain't gonna see it coming. You ain't gonna see it coming, come on!
哇… 唔…
Waaa! Whoo!
快点逃命吧
Running for your lives.
是时候放尊重点了
About time y'all showed some respect around here.
- 嗯？- 卡特 等师父来了再说
- Huh? - Carter, wait for the master.
哇 见鬼
Whoa! Damn!
嘿 对不起哥们 我还以为这里是厕所
Heh, I'm sorry, man. I thought this was the bathroom.
先走了
Sorry.
李 我遇到麻烦了 老兄
Lee, I got a big problem, man.
这个男孩肯定打激素了 头和贝瑞·邦德的一样大
This boy's on steroids. He got a head like Barry Bonds.
- 哦 糟糕 - 别这样 兄弟
- Oh, no. - Come on, man.
卡特 你还好吧？
Carter, are you OK?
李 李 阻止他 李
Lee, Lee, get him, Lee!
李 咱们赶紧离开这个鬼地方…
Lee, let's get the hell outta...
啊 我的脚
Aah! My bunions!
求你了兄弟 放我走吧 我爱中国人
Come on, man, let me go. I love Chinese people!
等等 我不想…
Wait. I don't...
中文"投降"怎么说？
How do you say "surrender" in Chinese?
好吧 我要把你切成一个大加州卷
OK. I'm about to slice you up like a giant California roll!
这老黑真有意思
Funny black man.
哦 见鬼
Ooh... Oh! Shit!
我要来真格的了
I'm not playing no more.
- 放手 - 卡特
- Lee, let go! - Carter!
放下 把我们放下
Down! Put us down!
让我下来 我错了
Let me down! I'm sorry!
- 啊 - 我错了 兄弟
- Aaaaah! - I'm sorry, man!
怎么成这样子了？
How the hell did we get in this mess?
立正
Attention!
敬礼
Salute!
有什么我能帮助的吗？
May I help you?
我们要问你几个问题 老头
We'll be asking the questions, old man.
- 你是谁？- "你"
- Who are you? - Yu.
- 不 不是我 是你 - 是的 我是"你"
- No, not me. You. - Yes, I am Yu.
你快回答我的问题
Just answer the damn questions.
- 你是谁？- 我告诉你了
- Who are you? - I have told you.
- 你聋了吗？- 不 "你"瞎了
- Are you deaf? - No, Yu is blind.
我不瞎 你才瞎了
I'm not blind, you blind.
- 我刚才就这么说的 - 你刚才说了什么？
- That is what I just said. - You just said what?
- 我没有说什么 我说"你" - 那就是我要问你的
- I did not say what, I said Yu. - That's what I'm asking you.
- "你"在回答你的问题 - 闭嘴
- And Yu is answering. - Shut up!
- 你 - 有什么事？
- You! - Yes?
不是你 是他
Not you, him!
- 你叫什么？- "我"
- What's your name? - Mi.
- 是的 就是你 - 我是"我"
- Yes, you! - I am Mi.
他叫"我" 我叫"你"
He is Mi, and I am Yu.
我真想使劲抽你屁股 老头 我快被你整疯了
And I'm about to whup your old ass, man, because I'm sick of playing games!
你 我 这里所有人的屁股 还有他的
You, me, everybody's ass around here! Him!
- 卡特 卡特 - 我真想踢他屁股
- Carter, Carter. - I'm-a kick his ass.
- 我快被整疯了 - 卡特 交给我处理吧
- I'm sick of this. - Carter, let me handle this.
- 李 不要 李 不要 - 卡特
- Lee. No, Lee. No! - Carter!
待在一边
Go.
师父 我是李督察 我有苏阳柜头的钥匙 我想打开看一下
今天早晨来了很多人 带了枪
搜查了苏阳的箱子 我不能阻止他们
你一定要赶快去找她
为什么？
因为他们打算用对付她爸爸的办法来对付她呀
咱们走
Let's go.
我不知道你喂他吃什么
I don't know what the hell you feeding him...
- 但是他长得太大只了 - 卡特 走吧
- but he is too damn big! - Carter. Go.
大家都去哪了？
Where is everyone?
警察都哪去了？
Where's all the damn cops?
- 李 - 警卫都去哪了？
- Lee. - Where's security?
他们都被叫走了
They were called away.
出… 出了什么事？
W... What's wrong?
卡特
Carter.
哦 事情不妙
Aw, this ain't good.
他们来找他了
They're coming for him.
我们怎么办？
What do we do?
不要
No.
No!
不许动 不然我把你屁股崩飞
Don't move, or I'll blow your ass cheeks off.
退后
Get back.
呃
Ugh!
是谁派你们来的？
Who sent you?
哦
Oh!
不许动
Don't move!
李 扔把枪给我
Lee, throw me a gun!
- 什么？- 扔把枪给我
- Huh? - Throw me a gun!
见鬼 李
Damn, Lee!
李 我还以为你在掩护我
Lee! I thought you had my back!
苏阳 再来一下
Soo Yung, one more!
李 我有麻烦了 我需要支援
Lee, I'm in trouble! I need some assistance.
接着
Here.
没子弹
It's empty.
什么？
What?
你看 我一直是你坚强的后盾
You see? I always got your back.
那你干吗还给我一把没子弹的枪？
Why the hell you give me an empty gun, then?
我当时不知道
I didn't know.
你差点害死我 李
You almost got me killed, Lee.
- 啊 啊 - 你是谁？谁派你来的？
- Ah! Ahh! - Who are you? Who sent you?
你是谁派来的啊？你是谁派来的啊？
Who sent you? Who sent you?
他到底在说些什么？
What the hell is that?
我想他在说法语
I think he's speaking French.
法语？什么样的中国人说法语？
French? What kind of Chinaman speak French?
告诉他别耍花招 说英语
Tell him to stop playing around and talk right.
我怎么告诉他？我又不说法语
How can I tell him? I don't speak French.
说英语 哥们
Talk right, man.
不 你是亚洲人 别这么丢人现眼了
No! You're Asian. Stop humiliating yourself.
你给我闭嘴 闭嘴 过来
Shut the hell up. Shut up. Come here.
我们需要和这个人单独待一会儿
We're gonna need a few minutes alone with this guy.
麻烦你找一个会讲法语的人过来 谢谢
Find someone here who speaks French, please.
说英语
Speak English!
呃 这位是楼上的礼拜堂的安格尼斯修女
Uh, this is Sister Agnes from the chapel upstairs.
她会说非常流利的法语 并且愿意为你们翻译
She speaks fluent French and has agreed to interpret for you.
修女 非常感谢你能帮忙
Sister, we appreciate you doing this.
很乐意
My pleasure.
安格尼斯修女 请问一下是谁派他来的
Sister Agnes, please ask who sent him.
他说你们两个都犯了一个大错误
He says you're both making a big mistake.
迟早有一天会求饶的
That one day soon you'll beg for mercy.
他还说…
He also said...
说什么？
What?
求你了 修女 我们必须知道
Please, Sister, we have to know.
性命攸关
There's lives at stake.
好吧 他说了一个N开头的词
Well, he used the N-word.
什么？N开头的词？
What? The N-word?
- 你告诉这个小杂… - 卡特
- You tell this little motherf... - Carter!
人家是修女
She's a nun.
修女 请告诉这个S开头的 我用F开头的词回敬他
Sister, you tell this piece of S-word that I will personally F-word him up.
他是不是说"黑鬼"？
Did he say "Negro"?
他又用了N开头的单词 并且这一次还"问候"了你的祖母
He used the N-word again, but this time he mentioned your grandmother.
你告诉他那他妈妈就是一个H
You tell him that his mama's a H!
卡特 我相信"妓女"这个词是W开头的
Carter, I believe "whore" is spelled with a W.
对 W 他的妹妹也是个W
Right. W. And his sister's a W.
他的祖母是两个W…
And his grandmama's a two-bit W...
因为她没有牙齿
who makes double because she got no teeth!
你告诉他我是这么说的
You tell him I said that.
他又说那个了？
Did he say it again?
不 这一次他用一个
No. This time he called...
意为"小猫"的单词称呼这位先生
this gentleman a word that means "cat"...
用一个音似"蛆"的单词称呼另一位
and another word that rhymes with "maggot."
什么？
What?!
好吧 你告诉他他是一个A.W.
Well, you tell him he's an A.W.
呃 李 "孔"是以H开头的
Uh, Lee, "hole" is spelled with a H.
我楼上就有字典
I have a dictionary upstairs.
就告诉他他没屁眼
Just call him an asshole.
他说你们两个死定了 就像韩和他的女儿
He says you've both been marked for death, like Han and the girl.
修女 请转过身去 你不会想看接下来这一幕的
Ooh. Sister, turn your back. You don't want to see this.
谁是"煞星"？怎样才能找到他？
Who is Shy Shen and how do we find him?
现在就告诉我们 不然我就把你的蛋蛋割下来塞到你的嘴里
Tell us right now or I'll cut your B's off and shove them in your mouth.
- 他的蛋蛋？- 他的蛋蛋 修女
- His beads? - His beads, Sister.
他的毛茸茸的 发臭的蛋蛋
His hairy, stinking beads.
给我说话
Tell me something now.
李 把枪给我 把枪给我 李
Lee, give me the gun. Give me the gun, Lee.
一切都结束了 兄弟 一切都结束了 好的
It's over, brother. It's over. OK.
"煞星"是谁？
Who is Shy Shen?!
他说了什么 修女？
What did he say, Sister?
他说"开枪吧"
He said "shoot me."
李 里面没有子弹
Lee, there's no bullets in here.
- 对不起 - 我正要杀人呢 哥们
- I'm sorry. - I am trying to kill somebody, man.
见鬼 好了
Damn. OK.
你最好现在就告诉我
You better tell me something right now.
我这就把你送上西天 哥们
I'll send you right to heaven, man.
- 我不管了 - 卡特
- I don't even care no more. - Carter.
我既然死定了 就没什么可失去的了
I'm marked for death. I ain't got nothing to lose.
就这样 修女 向上帝祷告 告诉他他很快就会有伴了
That's right, Sister. Call the Lord and tell him he about to have some company.
卡特 住手
Carter, stop.
快说
Tell me something!
- 卡特 够了 - 哦 她快祈祷完了
- Carter, enough. - Oh, she's almost done.
我主 原谅我的罪过吧
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned!
他说等等
He says wait!
- 他说了什么？- 罗斯福·德·弗兰克林大街50号
- What did he say? - 50 Franklin D. Roosevelt.
吉纳维芙
Genevieve.
谢谢你
Thank you.
非常高兴与你合作 修女
Nice working with ya, Sister.
随时奉陪 小子
Anytime, brother.
罗斯福·德·弗兰克林大街50号
50 FDR.
- 这是个地址 - 简直就是大海捞针
- It's an address. - It's a wild goose chase.
美国的所有城市都有以罗斯福命名的街道
Every city in America has a street named after Roosevelt.
- 吉纳维芙又是谁？- 我不知道
- And who is Genevieve? - I don't know.
苏阳 我们要带你离开这里
Soo Yung, we're getting you out of here.
- 为什么？- 这里对你来说不安全
- Why? - It's not safe for you here.
我不会离开他
I won't leave him.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
- 苏阳 - 瑞纳德先生
- Soo Yung. - Mr. Reynard.
我很高兴你父亲没事
I'm glad your father is OK.
我的人会寸步不离的保护他的
My people won't leave his side.
- 我向你保证 - 谢谢你
- You have my word. - Thank you.
那么 我们走吧
So, let's go.
- 啊 - 我这是要去哪里？
- Ah. - Wh... Where am I going?
我们要离开洛杉矶 这里对我们来说不安全
We're getting out of Los Angeles. It's not safe for us.
就几天 苏阳 我保证
Just a few days, Soo Yung. I promise.
你将跟着我和我的家人去巴黎
You'll come with me and my family to Paris.
好的
OK.
等等
Wait.
你们答应过我
You made me a promise.
不要忘了
Don't forget.
我的天啊
My God.
我们抓到了个只会讲法语的刺客
We got a assassin in custody who only speaks French...
一辆豪华轿车在法国领事馆前爆炸
a limo blows up at the French Consulate...
下一次世界刑庭会议 将于两天后在巴黎召开
and the next meeting of the World Court is in Paris, two days from now.
难道你想的和我想的一样？
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
是的
Yeah.
我们应该去斐济岛躲上一年…
That we go to Fiji, we hide out for a year...
隐姓埋名 做个吧台服务生之类的…
maybe change our names, get jobs as bartenders...
而我叫你木子
and I'm-a call you Kiko.
我们必须在"煞星"找到我们之前找到他
We have to find Shy Shen before he finds us.
我们也要去巴黎 不是吗？
We're going to Paris, aren't we?
是的 就在今晚
Yes. Tonight.
你知道法国女人平均34%的时间是裸体吗？
Did you know the average French woman is naked 34 percent of the time?
我们不是去见女人的
We are not going there to meet women.
你必须忘掉她 我会再给你找一个的
You have to forget about her, and let me hook you up.
你对伊莎贝拉那样 还想再给我找一个？
Hook me up? After what you did to Isabella?
那纯属于意外
It was an accident.
再说你又没有和她睡过觉
Besides, you never even slept with her.
多亏了你 原本有希望的
Thanks to you. It was going to happen.
但是你却给搅了
But you just had to ruin it.
我做了什么以至于这么严重？
What did I do that was so terrible?
你开枪击中了我的女朋友 射伤了她的脖子
You shot my girlfriend. In the neck!
我没什么好说的了
There's nothing else to say.
她又没有死
It's not like she died.
她的眼神还是那么无精打采 她仍在墨西哥餐厅工作
So she has droopy eyes. So she works at El Poco Loco.
那只是暂时的
That was temporary.
只要她能眨眼 特勤局就会立刻把她调回去
As soon as she could blink, the Secret Service took her back.
你知道你的问题出在哪吗？你需要休息 需要好好玩玩
You know what your problem is? You need to relax, have some fun.
你米饭吃的太多了 都开始便秘了
You have too much rice in your diet. You're constipated.
我就不该带你来
I never should have brought you.
面对现实吧 你需要我 兄弟
Face it, you need me, brother.
我不需要任何人 你也不要叫我兄弟
I don't need anyone. And please don't call me brother.
这是什么？
What is this?
巴黎地下男士俱乐部
Underground gentleman's club in Paris.
拉帕斯俱乐部？得了吧
"Club La Passe"? Forget it.
检查一下地址
Check out the address.
"罗斯福·德·弗兰克林大街50号"
"50 Franklin D... Roosevelt."
正如我说的 你需要我
Like I said, you need me.
小姐 请给我们一份鱼丸冻 和一些泻药
'Scuse me. Can we have one gefilte fish and some Ex-Lax?
我们的行李箱跑哪去了 哥们
Where the bags at, man?
打扰了 先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
我是反间谍局的特派员莱维 两位能否跟我走一趟呢？
Commissaire Revi of the DST. Would you please come with me?
为什么？
Why?
只是需要问你们几个问题
Just need to ask you a few questions.
哦 哦 哥们 见鬼
Oh! Oh! Man! Goddamn, man!
哦 哥们 这是我见过的最烂的机场
Oh! Man, this is by far the worst airport I ever been to.
哦
Oh!
- 喔 - 啊 哥们
- Ooph! - Ah, man!
好了听着 现在你们哪位可以告诉我…
Now that I have your attention, why don't you tell me...
你们这些警察来巴黎找什么？
what you cops are looking for here in Paris.
我给你说过了 我们是来度假的
I told you, man. We on vacation.
只是来看看风景
Just taking in the sights.
先生们 这是我的城市…
Gentlemen, this is my city...
如果两个破警察来这里 脑袋被三合会爆开花
and I'm responsible if two stupid cops come here...
我是要负责任的
and get their heads blown off by the triads.
现在我虽然没法逼你们回去 但是却可以给你们些忠告
Now, I can't force you to leave, but I can make the suggestion.
总之 我在你的夹克衫里 发现了这把肮脏的小手枪
After all, I found this dirty little gun inside your jacket.
这意味着你们两个可以在我这里 蹲上20年的牢
Which means you could both do 20 years in my jail.
我们彼此了解了吗？
Do we understand each other?
太好了 很高兴与你们两个见面
Excellent. It was wonderful meeting you both.
那么我们现在可以走了吗？
So we can go now?
这个花不了多久
This will just take a moment.
欢迎来到巴黎
Welcome to Paris.
哦 糟糕
Oh, shit.
- 啊 - 你们要去哪里？
- Ahh. - Where you go?
- 嗯 - 罗斯福 呃…
- Ugh. - 50 Franklin, uh...
德·弗兰克林大街50号
D. Roosevelt.
不 下车
No. Get out.
- 什么？- 我不载他这种人
- What? - I don't drive his kind.
- 我这种？- 美国人
- My kind? - Americans.
我不载美国人
I don't drive Americans.
- 但我是中国人 - 是的 但你们两个是一起的…
- But I'm Chinese. - Yeah, but you're with him...
他们是世上最暴力的人
and they're the most violent people on earth.
他们总是引起战争 总是滥杀无辜
Always starting wars, always killing people.
美国人让我感到恶心
Americans make me sick.
听者 伙计 我们现在没心情说这个
Look, man, we are not in the mood for this.
我和我的搭档 刚刚被一个法国佬侵犯
Me and my partner just got violated by a small Frenchman.
还带着一个超大的戒指
Wearing a very large ring.
你们这群可悲的罪犯 总是以武力解决问题
You're a pathetic bunch of criminals who always resort to violence.
总是欺负弱者
Always push around the little guy.
嘿 那都不是真的 美国人并不暴力
Hey, that stuff ain't true. America's not violent!
得了吧 美国就是一个笑话
Come on, America is a joke.
你们侵略越南失败了 侵略伊拉克也失败了
You lost in Vietnam, you lost in Iraq.
你们甚至连打篮球 也不是欧洲人的对手了
You can't even beat the Europeans in basketball anymore.
梦幻队已经死了
The Dream Team is dead.
哈哈 我没听清 伙计
Ha ha. I didn't hear you, man.
有种你再说说NBA 我赌你不敢 我赌你肯定不敢
Talk about the NBA again, I dare ya. I double-dare ya.
就连你们皮包骨头的女人都让我感到恶心
Even your skinny women disgust me.
- 哈里·贝瑞 - 哦 我已经受不了了
- Halle Berry. - Aw, hell no.
你扯的太远了
Now you done gone too far.
你想要暴力是吗 全身恶臭的法国佬？
You want violence, smelly Frenchman? Huh?
你想要暴力？好的 这就让你尝尝
Do you want violence? Well, you got it!
- 卡特 把枪放下 - 说你爱美国
- Carter, put the gun down. - Say you love America.
我爱美国 求你了 不要杀我
I love America. Please, don't kill me.
唱国歌
Sing the national anthem!
不是那个 唱美国国歌
Not that one, man! Sing the American one.
不会唱
Don't know it.
在这里等我们 乔治
Wait for us here, George.
唔啦啦 李
Ooh la la. Lee.
卡特 保持警惕
Carter, stay focused.
我们是来找吉纳维芙的
We're looking for Genevieve.
咱们分头行动 我负责女的
Let's split up. I'll take the women.
卡特 詹姆斯·卡特
Carter. James Carter.
我知道你也许不知道我在说什么…
I know you probably don't understand a word I'm saying...
但我要告诉你…
but I gotta tell you...
你是我一生中见过的最漂亮的女人
you're the most beautiful woman I ever seen in my life.
真想把你脱光 然后在你全身涂满奶油…
And I'd like to strip you down and butter you...
就像涂奇迹面包那样
like a slice of Wonder Bread.
给你刮腋下 并将你全身倒满蜂蜜
And shave your armpits and pour honey all over your naked body.
然后接下来的两个星期里 我将会像只饥饿的熊一样
And for the next two weeks pretend I was a hungry bear.
好吧 詹姆斯·卡特 我恰巧会讲六种语言
Well, James Carter, I happen to speak six languages.
其中就有英语？
One of them English?
你是玩还是不玩？
Are you in or out?
当然是玩啰
Money plays.
先生 下注最少是1000欧元
Sir, it's a thousand-euro minimum.
我还差多少
How much I'm short?
930欧元
930 euros.
- 唔 - 没关系
- Heh. - It's OK.
让他玩吧
Let him play.
谢谢你
Thank you.
开牌
Changez.
- 开牌 - 开牌
- Changez. - Changez.
开牌？
Changez?
我在找吉纳维芙
I'm looking for Genevieve.
也许我可以帮你
Maybe I can help you.
你知道我讨厌警察哪一点吗？
Do you know what I hate about cops?
即使和女人在一起…
Even when they're with a woman...
他们也忘不了抓人
they can't stop thinking about getting their man.
"煞星"是谁？
Who is Shy Shen?
看 我说吧
See what I mean?
到楼上来 警官 我会给你你想要的
Come upstairs, cop. I'll give you what you want.
- 再给我一张 - 先生 这是巴卡拉
- Hit me. - Monsieur, this is baccarat.
我知道
I know that!
你认为我不知道什么叫巴卡拉？
You think I don't know baccarack when I play it?
当我还是个孩子的时候 我就和我的朋友…
When I was a kid, me and my friends and I...
经常在魔术师强森剧院外闲逛…
used to hang out in front of the Magic Johnson Theater...
而且整夜的玩巴卡拉
and play baccarack all night long.
所以发牌啊
Now hit me.
三个K 看仔细了 我赢了
Three kings. Read them and weep.
三张K的话就是0点
Three kings is a zero.
你的手气太遭了 您输了
You have the worst possible hand. You lose.
什么？
What?
啊 夫人的是7点
Ah, madame has a 7.
他赢了10万欧元 了不起
She wins 100,000 euros. Bravo.
卡特先生 您似乎给我带来了好运
Mr. Carter, it appears you have brought me luck.
我希望能把这好运带到你的床上
I'd like to bring you breakfast in bed.
失陪了
Excuse me.
好样的 李
Way to go, Lee.
今天小男孩就要变成大男人了
Today, my boy becomes a man.
你为什么要帮助我
Why are you helping me?
或许我是在帮我自己
Maybe I'm helping myself.
我怎样才能找到吉纳维芙？
How do I find Genevieve?
我看你喜欢直入正题
I see you like to get right to it.
你知道"煞星"？
Do you know Shy Shen?
你想知道一个秘密吗 警官？
Would you like to know a secret, cop?
是的 请讲
Yes, please.
今天将有人葬身于此
Someone's gonna die here tonight.
就是你
And it's you.
快点 你这只卧虎 别把"龙"藏起来
Come on, crouching tiger, don't hide that dragon.
使劲 李 把她屁股翘起来
Do it, Lee. You tear that ass up.
你这个超级大变态
You are a super freak!
卡特
Carter!
哦
Oh!
- 快跑 - 哦
- Run! - Oh!
- 啊 - 对不起
- Ahh! - Sorry.
- 你有男朋友吗？- 卡特
- You got a boyfriend? - Carter!
开车
Start the car.
- 快开车 - 开快些
- Start the car! - Drive fast!
卡特 快看
Carter. Look!
嗯 乔治？开快些 伙计
Uh, George? We need you to go faster, man.
不 想都别想
No. Forget it.
你要是想杀我 那就来吧 来杀我吧
You wanna kill me, then go ahead, kill me.
- 啊 - 开快点
- Ahh! - Drive faster!
求你了 我害怕
Please! I'm scared!
乔治 你看美国电影吗？
George, you watch American movies?
- 嗯 - 好的 伙计
- Yeah. - OK, man. All right.
听着 你是超级特工
Listen, you're a super-spy.
超级特工
A super-spy.
好好开这辆车
Now drive this cab.
- 加油 - 好的
- Come on. - OK.
我是超级特工
I'm a super-spy.
哦 见鬼 乔治 开快些
Oh, shit, George. Go!
- 啊 - 乔治…
- Aah! - George...
乔治 听我的命令 就踩刹车
When I tell you to, hit the brakes.
就是现在
Now!
哦 他们有枪 李
Oh, they got guns, Lee!
- 呃 - 倒车
- Ungh! - Back up!
好样的 乔治
Way to go, George.
没事的
It's OK.
这个我来
I got this one.
哦 哇 他抓住了我的腿
Oh! Whoa! He's got my leg!
啊啊啊啊
Aaaah!
李 上帝啊
Lee! God!
- 啊啊啊啊 - 抓紧…
- Aaaaah! - Hold m...
啊
Ah!
回到你自己的车上去
Get your own damn cab.
哇唔
Ow!
李
Lee!
法国人是中立的 我不参与战斗
The French are neutral! This is not my fight!
我不参与…
This is not...
啊 李 我还活着
Ah! Lee, I'm alive.
我在恍惚中看到了自己的未来
My whole life flashed in front of me.
三年后我会娶一个中国女孩子做妻子
In three years I'll be married to a Chinese woman.
我们有三个孩子 长得很像你 只不过更黑一些
We had three kids looked just like you, only a little darker.
- 卡特 - 什么？
- Carter. - What?
把手举起来
Put your hands up.
你在说什么？
What you talking about?
哇
Whoa!
有人说当法国建这些下水道的时候
Some people say the modern world was invented...
现代社会便产生了
when the French built these sewers.
每小时有1000万加仑的水流过
10 million gallons pumped through every hour.
这是一个没有人曾经见过的奇迹
A marvel that no one ever sees.
欢迎来到巴黎 李
Welcome to Paris, Lee.
李 你认识这家伙？
Lee, you know this clown?
说啊 李 告诉他我是谁 别害羞啊
Go on, Lee. Tell him who I am. Don't be shy.
把他介绍给你的兄弟
Introduce him to your shyong dih.
兄弟？你兄弟？
Shyong dih? Your brother?
他不经常提起我
He doesn't talk about me much.
事实上 他一生都想着忘掉我
In fact, he's spent his whole life trying to forget me.
如果人们知道香港的大侦探李 有一个与法律作对的兄弟
How would it look if Hong Kong's great Inspector Lee...
大家会怎样想呢？
had a brother on the wrong side of the law?
你不再是我的兄弟了
You're not my brother anymore.
郴州的事情都忘了？
对 早就不记得了
在洛杉矶的时候 你可是放了我一条生路啊
那个时候你可以杀我的 但是你没有开枪 为什么？
因为你并没忘记过去
我没杀你是因为我不是杀手
让我还你个人情吧 李
Let me repay the favor, Lee.
我不会杀你 如果你答应今晚就离开巴黎
I'll allow you to live if you promise to leave Paris tonight.
就这么定了 谢谢你带我们参观下水道
You got a deal. Thank you for showing us the sewer.
听着 他是个无恶不作的大坏蛋 我们还是离开这个鬼地方吧
Listen, that's a badass suit. Let's get the hell outta here.
那韩和他的女儿呢？
What about Han and his daughter?
这个我帮不上什么
There is nothing I can do for them.
- 我别无选择 - 那我也别无选择
- I have no choice. - Then I have no choice.
好吧 我想他要留下 有谁要把我送到机场？
Well, I guess he's stayin'. Who wanna take me to the airport?
我们永远是兄弟 李
We'll always be brothers, Lee.
这辈子是 下辈子还是
In this life and the next.
告诉我 健二 谁是"煞星"
Tell me, Kenji, who's Shy Shen?
一个值得以死来捍卫的秘密
Some secrets are worth dying for.
哦 好的 明白了 好的
Oh. OK. A... All right. OK.
李 这到底是怎么了？
Lee, what the hell is going on?
快走
Go!
嗨 看着点 老兄
Hey, which way, man?
- 见鬼 李 门是锁着的 - 走这边
- Shit, Lee, it's locked! - Over here!
- 李 - 我们得跳下去
- Lee! - We have to jump!
- 呜 - 哦 那是下水道
- Ooph. - Oh, that's the sewer!
- 见鬼 我不干 李 - 没有办法
- Hell no, Lee! - No choice!
- 我宁可死 - 快点
- I'd rather die. - Come on!
哦
Oh!
该死
Shi-i-i-i-i-it!
我想杀了你 李
I'm gonna kill you, Lee!
晚上好 欢迎来到广场酒店
Bonjour. Welcome to the Plaza Athenee.
能为您效劳吗？
How may I help you?
真高兴再次见到你 好久不见了
It's great to see you again. It's been too long.
是啊 先生 好久不见了
Yes, far too long, sir.
听着 我们要一个大套房 有两张床 两个淋浴室…
Listen, I need a big suite, two beds, two showers...
还要一个按摩师 几件新衣服 和一套护理用品
a massage therapist, some new clothes and a case of Old Spice.
都是你的错 你为什么不告诉我健二的事？
It's all your fault. How come you didn't tell me about Kenji?
那与你无关
It was none of your business.
你别忘了 他们想要杀我
In case you missed it, man, people are trying to kill me.
我现在弄得浑身都是屎 之前
I'm covered in shit and some French cops whupped my ass...
被该死的法国警察用电话号码本打屁股…
with some Yellow Pages, man.
所以别给说与我无关
So don't tell me it ain't none of my business.
我们不在香港你该感到幸运了
You're lucky we're not in Hong Kong.
那儿的电话本比这厚两倍
Phone book is twice as big.
老兄 你为什么不告诉我你有个兄弟
Why you didn't tell me you had a brother, man?
噢 该死 不…
Oh, hell, no...
- 女士 - 嗯？
- Lady. - Oui?
这该死的狗刚才尿我身上了
This damn dog just pissed on me.
做得好
Good girl.
你知道我怎么想的吗？
You know what I think?
我觉得你对健二心怀歉意
I think you feel sorry for this guy.
或许在洛杉矶的时候 他不是逃走的
Maybe Kenji didn't get away in LA.
或许是你故意放他走的
Maybe you let him go.
在东京的时候 日本黑社会杀他全家
The yakuza killed his family in Tokyo.
他7岁的时候就被送到中国了
He was sent to China when he was 7.
寄放在我长大的那家郴州的孤儿院
He was put in Chenzhou, the orphanage where I grew up.
我们相依为命
We kept each other alive.
你们互相照顾 而且直到现在你还在保护他
You protected each other. And you're still protecting him.
我称他兄弟
I call him shyong dih.
他就像我的兄弟一样
He was like my brother.
后来我离开了他
And then I left him.
那是因为你被领养了 你别无选择啊
You was adopted. What choice did you have?
后来他成了街上的小混混
He ended up on the streets.
你是永远都无法理解的
You could never understand.
老兄 我理解 我也有一个兄弟
I understand, man. I got a brother.
我的弟弟培利
My little brother Perry.
我们过去是最好的朋友 现在我们连话都不说了
We used to be best friends. Now we don't even speak.
他觉得我向警察告发了他在车库斗鸡的事情
He think I tipped off the cops about his chicken fights in his garage.
你相信吗？就因为我的鸡在半决赛中输了
Can you believe that? My own brother think I'm a snitch.
我的亲弟弟居然认为我是个告密者
Just because my chicken lost in the semifinals.
其实我根本就不在意
I didn't even really care.
- 卡特 - 比赛输了一点不奇怪
- Carter. - Fight was fixed, man.
我的鸡和他的根本不是一个档次的
My bird was fighting a chicken that didn't make his weight.
可是它还是坚持下来了
And he still went the distance.
它很勇敢 而且吃起来也很美味
He had a lotta heart. And he was delicious.
最好由我自己来解决这件事情 这是私事
It's best if I do this on my own. This fight is personal.
让我帮你 老兄 听我说…
Lemme help you, man. I'm-a tell you right now...
不论健二说什么 都是骗你的
whatever Kenji's telling you, it ain't true.
- 他不是你的兄弟 - 你也不是我的兄弟
- He ain't your brother. - And you are not my brother.
没错
Fine.
我不是你的兄弟
I'm not your brother.
是的 我想要些炸鸡
Yes, I would like to order some fried chicken, please.
哦 还要一些红薯派
Oh, and some sweet-potato pie.
谢谢
Merci.
先生 这是你的汤
Enjoy your mu shu, sir.
- 谢谢 - 再见
- Merci. - Goodbye.
嗯 "吉纳维芙"
Hm. "Genevieve."
- 哦 - 你好啊 督察
- Oh. - Hello, Inspector.
雷纳德部长
Minister Reynard.
他们要杀我和我的家人
They want to kill me. Me and my family.
就在过去两个月里…
A dozen agents from the French secret police...
已经有一批法兰西特勤局的警员被谋杀了
have already been murdered... only this last month.
在这 在我自己城市里 已经在进行一场和三合会的斗争了
We are at war with the triads, right here in my own city.
煞星是谁？
Who is Shy Shen?
嗯 煞星… 煞星不是人名
Ah, Shy Shen... uh... Shy Shen is not a person.
它是个名单
It's a list.
- 名单？- 是的
- A list? - Yes.
每五年 三合会的老大们就会聚到一起
Every 5 years, the triad bosses come together...
在典礼上 他们选出组织的下一届领导人
for an election, and during that ceremony they choose the men who will lead the triads.
- 龙头老大 - 没错
- Dragon heads. - Yes.
然后由选出的13个龙头老大
13 dragon heads who will control...
控制着世界上最大的犯罪集团
the largest criminal organization in the world.
他们的名字都被记在叫着煞星的名单上
And their 13 names are inscribed on the list known as Shy Shen.
这个名单秘密代代相传
A list which has been handed down and kept secret... from generation to generation.
如果一旦名单上的名字被泄露…
If the names on that list were ever to get out...
那这个组织就不再是个秘密了
well, the secret society wouldn't be so secret anymore...
他们将被关键监狱 或被枪毙
and they would all end up in jail, or dead.
那这个名单是在巴黎某个地方吗？
And the list is somewhere in Paris?
一个名为"吉纳维芙"的女孩 曾和韩大使联系过…
A young lady named Genevieve made contact with Ambassador Han...
她应该知道名单的下落
and we believe she knows where it is.
督察 我需要你的帮助
I'm asking for your help, Inspector.
来完成韩大使未完成的事业
Finish what Ambassador Han started.
在三合会之前找到那个女孩 并找到"煞星"
Get to the girl before the triads do and you'll get Shy Shen.
听不懂 你是谁？
I don't understand. Who are you?
- 我是谁？- 对
- Who am I? - Oui.
我是巴布尔斯 新来的服装设计师
I'm Bubbles. The new costume designer!
谁看到吉纳维芙了？
Has anyone seen Genevieve?
她有自己化妆室
Uh, she has her own dressing room.
等等 巴布尔斯
Wait. Bubbles.
我们看起来还好吧？
Uh, do we look OK?
不不不
No. No, no.
这些服装太糟糕了
These costumes are terrible!
女士们 快点 我们有事情要做了
Ladies, please, we have work to do!
首先 我会给金发美女设计服装
First, I will dress the blondes.
然后是…
And then...
浅黑肤色的美女
the brunettes.
最后是
And finally...
混血儿们
the hybrids.
上天赋予了你们绝对的美貌
The Lord have truly bless you all with tremendous talent...
相信我
trust me.
你们其中一些人具有相当的潜力
And some of you have what I like to call... silver-dollar potential.
李 你在这干嘛？
Lee! What you doing here?
你在这又做什么？
What are you doing here?
- 我来找吉纳维芙的 - 我也是
- I found Genevieve. - So did I.
- 他们要杀她 - 什么？
- They're gonna kill her. - What?
你看
Look.
- 李 你负责灯光 我负责女孩 - 好的
- Lee, you get the lights, I'll get the girl. - Oh.
- 你的生命受到威胁 - 搞什么鬼？
- Your life is in danger. - What the hell's going on?
你再往前走一步的话 就再也回不来了
You step into that spotlight, it's the last step you ever gonna take.
下面有人要杀你
They're gonna kill you right now.
你是谁？
Who are you?
詹姆斯·卡特 洛杉矶警察局的
James Carter, LAPD.
对不起了 詹姆斯 是我个人秀的时间了
Sorry, James. It's time for my solo.
你现在最好和我一起走 美女
You gotta come with me now, girl.
怎么了？
What's happening?
把你的脏手拿开
Get your hands off me!
我们是韩大使的朋友
We are friends of Ambassador Han.
请相信我们
Trust us, girl.
计程车
Taxi.
Taxi!
- 快上车 - 是乔治
- Get in. - It's George!
快走
Go, go, go.
朋友们 我一整天都在找你们
I've been looking for you all day, my friend.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
别妄想了 乔治 我们不会赔偿的
Forget it, George. We're not paying for any damages.
哦 不 不 我不是要你们赔偿
Oh, no, no, no. I don't want you to pay.
我想为你们全程免费服务
I wanna ask if I could drive you full time no charge.
为什么？
Why you want to drive us?
今天的枪战太刺激了
Today was amazing. The guns, the shooting.
让我明白了什么是真正的美国人
Now I understand what it is to be an American.
求你们了 让我当你们的司机吧
Please, I'm begging you. Let me be your driver.
让我今晚也杀一个尝尝
Let me kill someone tonight!
你永远都当不了美国人的 知道吗？
You'll never be an American, OK?
如果有必要的话 我一天就只喝这个了
I'll drink this shit all day if I have to.
就给我一次机会吧
Just give me a chance.
好吧 好吧 把我们带到广场酒店 快
All right, fine. Get us to the Plaza, fast.
没问题 老大
You got it, boss.
坐稳了
Hold on.
所以你认为她从三合会那偷到了煞星？
So you think she stole this Shy Shen list from the triads?
只有一种办法可以知道
Only one way to find out.
你和我想的一样？
You thinking what I'm thinking?
我们需要和她谈谈 让她放松下来
We need her to talk. Get her relaxed.
或者我们可以开瓶酒
Maybe open up some wine from the minibar.
或者我们可以放部A片看看
Maybe we should put on a dirty movie.
- 李 - 一部只要9.95元
- Lee! - Only 9.95.
这是我们找到煞星的好机会
This our chance to find Shy Shen.
我进去了
I'm going in.
你这是怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
等等 我和你一起
Wait, let me go with you.
有些事由我一个人来就好了
Some things a man has to do on his own.
你还好吧？
You OK?
健二肯定发现我做的事了
Kenji must have figured out what I've done.
我死定了
I'm as good as dead.
你偷了名单 对吗？你想把它卖给韩大使？
You stole the list, didn't you? You tried to sell it to Han?
不是这样 我是他们中的一员
You don't get it. I'm one of them.
如果我死了 你也必死无疑
And if I'm dead, you're dead.
嘿 我们现在很安全 没人知道我们在这
Hey, we're safe. No one knows we're here.
放松点
Just relax.
没有人是安全的
No one is safe.
我被盯上了
I'm marked.
相信我
Trust me.
我为什么要相信你？
Now why should I trust you?
中国有句话说: 驴唇不对马嘴
As the Chinese say...
什么意思？
What does that mean?
"驴子的唇安不到马的嘴上"
"A donkey's lips will not fit on a horse's mouth."
我还是不知道什么意思
I'm not sure how that applies.
我只是在想 你的嘴唇很美
Well, I was just thinking you had nice lips.
就这样
That's all.
你今天救了我的命 谢谢你 卡特
You saved my life today. Thank you, Carter.
噢 算了 叫我詹姆斯
Oh, please. Call me James.
或猛男也行
Or Stallion.
很久没人挺身而出救我了
No one's saved me in a long time.
我该怎么报答你？
How can I repay you?
你有20块钱吗？
You got 20 bucks?
10块也行
How about ten?
噢
Oh, man. Mmm.
- 詹姆斯 - 嗯？
- James. - What?
- 我很坏 - 我也很坏
- I'm bad. - I'm bad too.
我是个坏女孩
I'm a bad girl.
哈利路亚
Hallelujah!
哦 就这样 宝贝
Oh, yeah. That's it, baby. Yeah. Uh-oh.
噢…就是这样 宝贝
Ha ha. Oh, yeah. That's it, baby.
哦 尽情咬那只耳朵吧 惩罚它吧
Oh, yeah. Bite that ear. Punish that ear.
做你想做的
Do what you wanna do.
哦 宝贝…喔 喔 等等
Oh, baby... Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
我的咪咪很敏感 你得小心点
My nipples are sensitive. Be careful down there.
我从没和美国人睡过
I've never been with an American man before.
我也没有
Neither have I.
和你在一起我觉得很安全 你想要我吗？
I feel so safe with you. Do you want me?
哈 "现在做两次 在浴室做一次" 用法语怎么说？
Ha. How you say "Twice now and once in the shower" in French?
在这等我 我先去趟浴室
Wait here. I'm going to the bathroom.
让我自己更舒服些
Make myself more comfortable.
需要我陪你吗？
You need some matches?
别动 我一会就回来
Don't move. I'll be right back.
你好 客房服务吗？
Hello, room service?
给我送瓶蜂蜜还有几罐红牛
Send me up a bottle of honey and some Red Bull.
喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
怪不得单车手阿姆斯特朗总是要来这参加比赛
No wonder Lance Armstrong came all the way here to ride a bike.
非常感谢
Merci beaucoup.
哦 宝贝 来吧
Oui, baby, oui!
噢 耶
Oh, yeah.
你不会骗我吧 宝贝
Voulez... vous coucher avec moi, baby?
我爱你
Je t'aime.
你可愿意
Voulez-vous.
噢 耶
Oh, yeah.
我爱你宝贝 我爱你
Je t'aime, baby, je t'aime!
住手 别动
Freeze! Don't move!
噢 见鬼 活见鬼
Ah! Shit! Damn!
- 我中枪了 - 没事的 没事的
- I'm shot. - It's OK, it's OK.
只是皮外伤 没事的
It's just a flesh wound. It's OK. Gen...
吉纳维芙 吉纳维芙 让我帮你
Genevieve, Genevieve, let me help you.
- 让我帮你 宝贝 - 哦 真的很抱歉
- Let me help you, baby. - I'm terribly sorry.
- 我没事 - 你去哪？
- I'm OK. - Where you going?
见鬼
Je... Damn.
现在我们扯平了了 你是故意的吧
So we even now, huh? Is that it?
我开枪打你的女友 你现在报复我？
I shoot your girl, you shoot my girl?
我是来救你的
I was trying to save your life.
你就不能再等五分钟吗？
Well, you couldn't wait five minutes?
我们… 我们马上就要做爱了 老兄
We... We was about to make love, man!
却被你搅乱了
And you ruin it.
他们会追着来的 我们得离开这 马上
They will be coming for us. We have to get out of here now.
听到了吧 我们必须马上离开这
You hear that? We have to get out of here now.
- 见鬼 李 去死 - 抱歉
- Damn, Lee! Damn you. - Sorry.
下次我要自己一个房间
Next time I'm getting my own damn room.
让他们出去 乔治
Get them out, George.
这些人很危险 他们都流血了
These people are danger, they're bleeding.
你怎么可以把他们带回家呢？
How can you bring them to our home?
波莱特 有些事你必须知道
Paulette, there is something you should know.
我不再是以前的那个我了
I'm not what you think I am.
难道你是同性恋不成？
Are you telling me you're gay?
我是想告诉你 我现在是美国间谍
I'm trying tell you... l'm an American spy.
哈 你是间谍？
Ha. You a spy?
是的 我是警察雇的秘密间谍
Yes, I'm working undercover with the police.
我们在破一宗大案
We're about to crack a big case!
行了 乔治 闭嘴吧
Shut your mouth, George. Not another word.
你和你父亲一样 只是一个笨蛋司机
You're a stupid cab driver, like your father was a stupid cab driver.
就凭你能破什么大案？
What kind of case could you crack?
无可奉告
Can't talk about it.
从现在开始 别再干预我的事情
From this moment on, don't ever ask me about my business!
跟我走 快点
Come with me, schmuck. Now.
我们必须离开这座城市
We need to get out of the city.
我们哪都不去 除非你告诉我们到底是怎么回事
We're not going anywhere till you tell us exactly what's going on.
你是不是从三合会那偷了那份名单？
Did you steal that list from the triads?
吉纳维芙 告诉我们真相 否则我们无法帮你
Genevieve, we cannot help you until you tell us the truth.
煞星在哪？
Where is Shy Shen?
就在这
It's right here.
我的天 她是个男人
Holy mother of Jesus! She's a man.
我居然和这该死的法兰西男人上了二垒
I went to second base with a damn Frenchman.
简直就是《哭泣的游戏》
It's The Crying Games.
我成了断背卡特了 噢 我的天
I'm Brokeback Carter. Oh, God.
我不是男人 这只是假发而已
I'm not a man. It's just a wig.
你肯定吗 嗯？
You sure about that? Huh?
李 快点过去检查下她有无凸出物？
Lee, go over there and check the hardware.
如果她身上有什么不该有的凸出物…
If she got anything in her bag bigger than a three-iron...
我们就踢爆他的屁股
we gonna beat his ass!
我是女人 詹姆斯 一个需要逃命的女人
I'm a woman, James. A woman who needs a way out.
你们要帮我
You have to help me.
- 煞星在你那？- 不
- You have Shy Shen? - No.
我就是煞星
I am Shy Shen.
在古代 每当三合会选出新的领导人…
In ancient times, when the triads would select new leaders...
他们就把名字秘密纹在一个女人头上…
they would secretly tattoo the names onto a woman...
这个女人带着名单
a woman who could carry the list of Shy Shen...
走遍中国的35个省
to the 35 provinces of China.
让三合会的成员都知道新领导是谁
When her journey ended and the new leaders were informed...
任务完成后 这个女人的头就会被砍下来并被永远埋葬
the woman would be beheaded and buried forever.
没有记录 也没有证人
No records, no witnesses.
这是什么鬼传统啊？
What type of tradition is that?
他们不知道用传真机吗？
Have these guys ever heard of a damn fax machine?
健二让我这么做的 他说这是件光荣的事
Kenji made me do it, said it was a great honor.
我这么做是为了他 为了兄弟之情
I wanted to do it for him. For the brotherhood.
那你为什么要把名单告诉韩大使？
Then why did you send the names to Han?
因为我觉得国际刑事法庭可以保护我
Because I thought the World Court could protect me.
现在我才明白 没人可以保护我
But now I see... nobody can.
嘿 你怎么会这么蠢 女士
You are messed up in some weird shit, lady.
哦 不 哥们 你到底是男是女？
I mean man. Whatever the hell you are.
我是女人
I'm a woman!
他们会派军队来杀我的 为了保护他们的组织
And they will send a army to kill me. To protect their way.
哦 我们可对付不了军队 李
You know what? We can't fight no army, Lee.
谁来保护我？我是说 我们
Who gonna protect me? I mean us?
我知道个地方
I know a place.
我不能在这等你们出来了 很抱歉
I won't be here when you come out. I'm sorry.
我老婆说我当不了间谍 我要回去吃晚饭了
My wife says I can't be a spy, that I have to be home for dinner.
事实上我本来就是个司机 仅此而已
The truth is I'm a driver. Nothing more.
这就是我的命
This is my destiny.
我永远都无法知道当美国人的滋味了
I will never know what it's like to be an American.
也不会知道杀人是什么感觉了
Never know what it feels like to kill for no reason.
乔治 没事的
George, it's OK.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见 祝你们好运
Au revoir. And good luck.
- 再见 - 再见 乔治
- Au revoir. - Bye, George.
瑞纳德部长
Minister Reynard.
我们找到煞星了
We have it.
煞星名单？真不可思议
The Shy Shen list? This is incredible.
有人说它是个神话
Some people said it was a myth.
不 它不是神话 我见过 感觉过
Naw, it's no myth. I've seen it. Felt it.
还吻过 但不是法兰西式的吻
Kissed it. But I didn't French kiss it.
你不知道这有多危险吗
You do understand how dangerous this is?
你会保护我们的 对吗？
I was gonna use protection.
我们可以请求警方帮助吗？
Can we go to the police?
当地大部分警察都被三合会控制了
The triads control too many of them here.
必须想办法让你们离开这
We have to get you out of the country.
好了 亲爱的…
Now, my dear...
可不可以摘下假发 让我们看看煞星的样子？
would you mind taking off that wig and showing us Shy Shen?
我们从没说过她就是煞星名单
We never told him she was the list.
看看 13个具有几百年传统意义的名字
Look at that. 13 names linked to centuries of tradition.
这个秘密组织存在的唯一证据
The only real proof that their secret world exists.
杀了他们
Kill them.
吉纳维芙 缴了他们的枪
Genevieve, get their guns.
我早告诉你他不是好人 我没告诉你吗？
I told you he was bad. Didn't I tell you?
没有
No.
我正想告诉你的
Well, I was thinking it.
你不觉得大使馆前的爆炸有问题吗？
The explosion at the embassy.
作为国际刑事法庭的主席
As head of the World Criminal Court...
我自然会成为他们的目标
it would make sense for me to be a target.
那晚你为什么来我的房间？
Why did you come to my room?
我本来以为 那晚吉纳维芙死定了
Genevieve was going to be killed.
如果你也死在那场枪火之中 那么这次调查就可以结束了
Having you die in the crossfire would put an end to the investigation.
现在 则是另一种结局了
Now, it will end another way.
哈哈 一切都结束了 瑞纳德
Ha ha. It's over, Reynard.
你知道老年人蹲监狱是什么滋味吗？
You know what it's like for old men in prison?
他们管你叫大伯 让你在图书馆工作
They call you "pops." They make you work in the library.
到时你就只能与那些老鼠为伴了
Your best friend? Gonna be a mouse.
我不会去坐牢的
I'm not going to prison.
电话响了 督察
You have a phone call, Inspector.
兄弟 你好啊
Hello, brother.
做个交易怎么样
I'd like to make a trade.
我的朋友在洛杉矶获得一样东西
Some friends of mine came across something in Los Angeles.
很值钱的东西
Something very valuable.
李
Lee.
救救我
Help me, please.
明白了吗？
Do we understand each other?
你想要什么？
What do you want?
煞星
Shy Shen.
今晚 你和吉纳维芙单独来见我
You and Genevieve will meet me alone tonight.
如果让我看到你的搭档或是其它警察的话 就等着收尸吧
If I see your partner or any other cops, the girl dies.
在哪见？
Where?
朱斯旺饭店 午夜12点 别迟到了
Jules Verne restaurant, midnight. Don't be late.
他把女的带来了 叫电梯下去接他们
欢迎参加聚会啊 李
Welcome to the party, Lee.
今晚就让我们庆祝煞星的归来
Tonight we celebrate the return of Shy Shen...
还有我兄弟归来吧
and the return of my brother.
苏阳在哪？
Where is Soo Yung?
这剑和我们一样有着过去
This sword has a past.
有伤痛 有流血
And like ours, it has seen much pain, much blood.
几百年前 三合会的人
Hundreds of years ago the triads would kill their enemies...
会在敌人身上砍100刀再杀他
with 100 cuts to the body.
他们非常小心的避开所有主动脉
They would be very careful to avoid any major arteries...
这样可以让敌人尽可能多活一会
so that the victim would stay alive for as long as possible.
你刚才被砍了第一刀
You have just experienced your first cut.
如果苏阳有什么事的话
If anything happens to Soo Yung...
你永远都不会杀我的 李 这点我们都知道
You could never kill me, Lee. We both know that.
你什么都不知道
You know nothing about me.
我知道你没有妻子 没有孩子 没有家庭
I know you have no wife, no children, no family.
早在郴州我们还是小孩的时候 你就死了
Your life ended when we were kids, back in Chenzhou.
你和我一样 一无所有
You have nothing. Just like me.
你错了
I wouldn't say nothing!
他还有我这个兄弟
He has me.
同父异母而已
His brother from another mother.
苏阳在哪？
Where is she?
好好欣赏吧
Enjoying the view.
苏阳
Soo Yung!
李
Lee!
放了她
Let her go.
你想怎么样？
What the hell is wrong with you?
你想死吗 健二？
Do you wanna die, Kenji?
快把她放下来
Get her in here!
卡特 把枪放下
Carter, drop the gun.
快把她从绳索上放下来 否则我一枪毙了你
Get her off that damn rope, or I'm shooting you...
别威胁我
and the damn Temptations.
马上
Right now!
啊 不 李
Oh, no! Lee!
李
Lee.
- 快点照做 - 放她下去
- Do it! - Put her down!
我是认真的
I'm serious!
不是开玩笑
I'm not playing!
你不是我的兄弟
You ain't my damn brother.
健二
Kenji.
- 把枪放下 - 不
- Drop the gun. - No.
把枪放下 卡特
Drop it, Carter.
见鬼
Shit.
Damn it.
今晚我将失去一个兄弟
Tonight I lose a brother.
打倒他 李
Get him, Lee!
真想把你屁股踢爆 健二
Gonna get your ass kicked, Kenji.
加油 杀了他
Come on, kill him already!
李 他要是你兄弟 就阉了他让他当你姐
Lee, he might be your brother, but turn him into your sister.
小心
Watch out!
耶
Yeah!
老兄 给我过来
Bring your little ass here. Come here.
啊
Aaaargh.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
李？李
Lee? Lee!
坚持住 我来了
Hold on, I'm coming!
放开我
Get the hell off me.
噢
Oh.
耶 李
Yeah, Lee!
见鬼
God da...
够了 健二
Enough, Kenji!
你还等什么？动手吧
What are you waiting for? Do it!
放手吧
Let go.
否则我们两个都会死
Or we're both gonna die.
不 我可以救你
No! I can save you.
再见了 李
Goodbye, Lee.
不 健二
No, Kenji!
不
No!
我来了 苏阳
I'm coming, Soo Yung!
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God!
为什么我要做这种事情啊？
What the hell am I doing up here?
啊 救命
Aah! Help.
冷静点 女士 没必要这么做
Stay cool, lady. This doesn't have to end this way.
停下 停下 女士
Don't do it. Don't do it, lady.
你敢
Don't you do it!
想想你在干什么吧
Think about what you doing.
求求你
Please.
求求你 不
Please. No.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey!
警官 你想知道一个秘密吗？
Would you like to know a secret, cop?
不想
No.
求求你
Please.
啊 哦 不 不
Aaah! Oh, no! No!
不
No!
李 你刚才真该在这 他们败的一塌糊涂
Lee! You should've seen us, man. We whupped their ass.
苏阳
Soo Yung!
我没事
I'm OK.
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
快去报警
Call the police.
卡特
Rah! Hah! Carter!
坚持住
Hold on!
- 抓住 - 李 拉我上去
- Hang on! - Lee! Reel me in.
- 抓住了 - 黑人不会飞的
- I got you! - Black people don't fly.
拉我上去 拉我上去
Get me up. Get me up.
加油啊 老兄 快点
Come on, man. Hurry up.
哦 李 拉我上去
Oh! Lee! Get me outta here!
别放手啊
Don't let go of that flag!
- 哈 - 谢谢 李
- Ah. - Thank you, Lee.
卡特 抓紧旗子
Carter! Hold on to the flag!
等等 不要啊
Wait, no, no, no, no, no, no!
李 如果我们没死的话 我一定要杀了你
Lee, I'm gonna kill you if we don't die!
哦 天哪 上帝 救救我们
Oh, dear Lord, please! Baby Jesus, help us!
李 你在哪？
Lee! Where you at?
我溺水了 我溺水了
I'm drowning! I'm drowning!
李 快点把这东西弄开
Get this thing off me, Lee!
- 卡特 - 嗯？
- Carter. - What?
我再也不便秘了
I'm not constipated anymore.
把手举起来
Put your hands up.
吉纳维芙
Genevieve.
嘿 老兄 你是国际刑事法庭的主席啊
Hey, man, you're the head of the World Court.
你想干嘛 像杀动物一样把我们杀死吗？
What you gonna do, shoot us down like animals?
我们可是警察
We're police officers.
没错 可是你们刚才杀了这个女孩
Yes. And you two just killed this girl.
打得她脑袋开花
Blew her brains out.
- 卡特 - 住手
- Carter! - Don't do it!
卡特
Carter.
- 你还好吧 - 把枪放下
- You all right? - Put the gun down.
我一路跟着你们
I followed you.
结案
Case closed.
干得好 老兄
Good job, man.
嘿 你要敢再碰我
Hey, man! You touch me again...
就得请我吃晚饭还有看电影
you gonna owe me dinner and a movie.
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
我们终于粉碎了三合会
It appears we have finally brought down the triads.
- 我们？ - 你什么也没做
- We?! - You didn't do shit.
我的屁股还疼着呢
My butt still hurts.
美国人和法国人
The Americans and the French...
应该像兄弟一样团结起来
need to work together in the spirit of brotherhood.
这样任何事我们都能解决
Together, we can do anything.
任何事
Anything!
他说的没错 李 我们一起可以做任何事
He's right, Lee. Together, we can do anything.
你负责那边…
You go this way...
我负责这边…
And I'll go that way.
没错 李 在过去三年中
That's right, Lee. For the last 3 years...
我研究了古代的教战利品的方法
I've studied the ancient teaching of booty. Ev...
噢 战利品
Oh, booty.
奶酪
Cheese!
"奶酪？"
"Cheese"?
怎么了？
What?
- 住手 - 住手
- Freeze. - Oh, freeze!
只要她还会眨眼睛 海味局…
As soon as she could blink, the s... seafood service...
- 海味… - 是秘密情报局
- Seaf... seafood... - Secret Service.
只要她…还会眨眼睛…
As soon as sh... she could blink...
海味局… 嗯…
the sheafood shervish... Uh, swa...
秘密情报局
Secret Service.
海…
The ssssseaf...
是"秘密" 不是"海味"
Secret, not seafood.
我知道"海味"
I know seafood.
- 我也知道"秘密" - 秘密
- I know secret. - Secret.
- 秘密 - 秘密 对吧？
- Secret. - Secret. See?
但是这些单词连在一起的时候 就变成"海味"了
But when everything together, it become a seafood!
开始
Action!
- 对不起 真的很抱歉 - 它掉下来了
- I'm sorry! So sorry. - It came off.
开始
Action!
- 哦 见鬼 你还好吧 - 嗯 没事
- Oh, shit. You all right? - Yeah, good.
我的错…拳王阿里的动作来了
That was my... Muhammad Ali swing, man!
耶 宝贝
Yeah, baby!
哦…
Ooh.
- 就是这把 - 没错
- That's the one, Mama. - That would have been it.
我恨死你了 健二
I'm sick of you, Kenji.
从电影一开始 你就想尽办法要杀我们
You been trying to kill us ever since the start of this damn movie.
开始
Action.
没事吧？
You OK?
她的眼睛有些萎靡 她…
So her eye is a little droopy now and she's...
所以她现在在…上班
So she's working for El Loc... Lar El Poco.
- 哈哈哈 - 不好意思
- Ha ha ha. - I'm sorry.
是"墨西哥餐厅"
It's El Pollo Loco.
所以她现在在墨西哥餐厅上班
So sh... now she works at El Lolo Poco.
墨西哥餐厅
El Pollo Loco.
El Lo... Loro Poco. Uh.
墨西哥厅餐
El Poco Loco.
墨西哥餐厅
El Loco Poco.
所以她现在在…上班 所以什么？
So... so she works at Elo... Loco Poco, so what?
而且 她现在在…上班
And... So she works for El L... Loro Poco.
- 哈哈哈 - 墨西哥餐厅
- Ha ha ha. - El Pollo Loco.
这部分删了吧
No, we gonna go past that...
因为今晚我肯定搞不定的
...because I'm not getting that tonight.
墨西哥餐厅
El Pollo Loco.
呃… 哇 你好厉害
El... Ohh! Jackie!
墨西哥餐厅
El Pollo Loco!
妈妈走了
The mom's gone.
或者我们可以看一部A片
Maybe we should put on a dirty movie.
李
Lee!
- 我喜欢有故事情节的那种 - 什么？
- I like the ones with a story. - What?
- 我喜欢有衣帽间场景的那种 - 什么？
- I like the one with a locker-room scene. - What?
我喜欢有监狱场景的那种
I like the one with a prison scene.
我喜欢有淋浴场景的那种
I like the one with a shower scene.
我喜欢有白人女孩的那种
I like the ones with a white girl.
我晕了
I'm into feet.
我喜欢有马的那种
I like the one with the horses.
- 什么意思？- 见鬼
- What's that mean? - Damn.
他教我的都是什么？
What he teach me?
没错 再来一个 再来一个 最后一个了
That's it, one more, one more. Last one.
你在教我说脏话吗？
Are you teaching me a bad word?
我喜欢有长发美女的那种
I like the one with hairy woman.
你怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
我也不知道 布雷特告诉…
I don't know. Brett Ratner tell...
- 布雷特教我的 - 他什么都教你啊
- teach me that. - He'll teach you anything.
你不是我的兄弟
And you're not my brother.
我不是你的兄弟？
I'm not your brother?
我们一起经历了这么多
All the stuff we've been through?
尖峰时刻Ⅰ 尖峰时刻Ⅱ？
Rush Hour 1, Rush Hour 2?